Guide to the George Champion Papers, 1925-2019, MS 3241
New-York Historical Society
- Correspondence—Professional, 1933-1990, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  • Krulak, Victor H. (1962 June 18, Nov. 1, 2; 1963 May 28, 31; 1965 April 21, 23, May 4 [address by], 17, Oct. 31, Nov. 3; 1966 Jan. 24, Aug. 3, Sep. 14, Nov. 12 [postcard], 16)
  • Lifschultz, David K. (1986 July 30)
  • Lindsay, John V. and Robert F. Wagner (1973 March 8, 12, 20)
  • Martinuzzi, Leo S. (1969 Oct. 24)
  • Medlin, John G. Jr. [to Carla Knobloch] (1987 Feb. 17, March 10, 12, April 1)
  • Milbank, Jeremiah (1983 Oct. 7)
  • Milliken, Roger (1983 Nov. 14, 29)
  • Nixon, Richard M. (1989 June 1)
  • Palmer, Dave R. (1989 June 16)
  • Peale, Norman Vincent (1971 Dec. 15)
  • Perkins, Gilbert H. (1960 Dec. 13)
  • Perry, John D. (1933 April 13)
  • Powell, Lewis F. Jr. (1971 April 17, 20, 21, 26)
  • Reagan, Ronald (1975 Jan. 29)
  • Roberts, Clifford (1973 July 4, Aug. 22)
  • Rockefeller, David (1969 March 4; 1977 April 8, 14)
  • Selden, Lynde (1961 March 7, 8, 14)
  • Spurr, Gregory W. Jr. (1977 Feb. 14, 15)
  • Stans, Maurice H. (1975 Aug. 13)
  • Thomas, Lowell (1979 Aug. 13)
  • Wallace, DeWitt (1975 Oct. 2)
  • Wells, Kenneth (1965 March 3, 8)
- Dartmouth College sweater, 1926 (Offsite-box 4)
  Green wool sweater, with white "1926" appliquéd across chest.
  Restricted
  This item is in fragile condition and should not be handled.
- Eisenhower College—Fundraising, 1968-1973, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  Contains correspondence, financial and progress reports, and fundraising pleas for Eisenhower College, the small college named for the 34th president in Seneca Falls, New York. Champion was general chairman of the Tribute of a Grateful Nation Fund Committee, a group tasked with raising private funds in support of the college. See also Champion's correspondence with Dwight D. Eisenhower and Mamie Doud Eisenhower in Box 1, Folders 12-15.
- Freedoms Foundation, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 19)
  Undated tear sheet with group photograph and text "Announcement has just been made by President Wells that Lt. Colonel John Glenn, USMC, has been elected to the Board of Directors of Freedoms Foundation. Here—at the last Board Meeting, Glenn, who attended meeting, is talking to Chairman Eisenhower. Left to right, Wells, Glenn, Eisenhower, Champion, Belding."
- Investment Forum—Press coverage, 1966 October 28, 31; November 2 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 20)
  Press Coverage, Investment Forum, Mr. George Champion, Chairman, The Chase Manhattan Bank, N.A., October 28, 31, November 2, 1966. London, Frankfurt, Paris.
- Invitations and programs, 1952-1972 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 21)
  • List of Passengers, R.M.S. Queen Mary, First Class, from New York to Cherbourg and Southampton, Wednesday, June 11, 1952.
  • List of First Class Passengers, The New S.S. United States, Maiden Voyage from Southampton... July 10, 1952.
  • General of the Army Dwight D. Eisenhower, Mr. Basil O'Connor, Mr. George Champion, on behalf of the National Advisory Council... welcome you to the 85th Anniversary Dinner of Tuskegee Institute... Sep. 29, 1966.
  • Luncheon given by Mr. and Mrs. George Champion, Mr. and Mrs. David Rockefeller, in honor of Special Delegates Attending the 1966 Annual Meetings of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the International Monetary Fund, Oct. 2, 1966.
  • Mr. & Mrs. David Rockefeller request the pleasure of your company at the marriage reception of their daughter Neva Goodwin and Mr. Walter Jacob Kaiser, Saturday, Dec. 17th [1966], at half after four o'clock, Hudson, Pines, Pocantico Hills, New York.
  • The International Cardiology Foundation, International Gold Heart Award Dinner, A Tribute to Elmer H. Bobst marking his 85th birthday, Dec. 15, 1969.
  • Dinner in Honor of Mr. Bernard Jay Lasker by Vice President and Mrs. Agnew, Aug. 10, 1970.
  • The President [of the United States] requests the pleasure of the company of Mr. Champion at dinner on Thursday evening, Nov. 5, 1970.
  • The President and Mrs. Nixon request the pleasure of your company for an evening of Christmas entertainment at The White House on Friday, Dec. 18, 1970 [with mailing envelope, RSVP card, and program].
  • The Marriage of Patricia Nixon and Edward Finch Cox, The White House, June 12, 1971 [program, with letter enclosing White House parking permit].
  • Committee Dinner of the Second Panel Sheriffs Jury, Thursday, January twentieth, Nineteen hundred and seventy-two... George Champion.
  • The President and Mrs. Nixon request the pleasure of the company of Mr and Mrs Champion at dinner on Friday evening, Jan. 28, 1972.
- Manuscripts, 1969-1984, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 22)
  • Victor Riesel, "Special Police Commissioners: Black Panthers Call Conference to Launch Wide Fight for 'Community Control' of Police" [1969?]. [With an editorial by William Randolph Hearst Jr.]
  • Thomas R. Shepard Jr., "The Disaster Lobby" (1971 Jan. 28).
  • George Champion, "A Statement of Principles We Consider Necessary for the Reestablishment of Confidence by the Business Community in New York City" (1974 June 24).
  • Henry C. Wallich, "LDC Debt—To Worry or Not to Worry" (1981 June 2).
  • Henry C. Wallich, "Small Banks Can Make It, With Some Ingenuity" (1981 Sep. 14).
  • George Champion, "New York City's greatest asset.. ." (1976 Nov. 8).
  • [George Champion?], "Banking failures and excessive loan losses.. ." (1983 Nov. 30).
  • [George Champion?], "Banking failures and excessive loan losses.. ." (1983 Dec. 2).
  • "A Positive Program for Commercial Banks," [1984].
  • [George Champion?], "Comments on Federal Regulations of Financial Services at the Request of the Vice President," (undated).
  • [George Champion?], "Four imperatives for the business community.. ." ([year lacking] June 15).
  • [George Champion?], "On Building a Constituency" (undated).
  • [George Champion?] "Our Troubled City: What Business Can Do" (undated).
- Media coverage, 1961-1982 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 23)
  Interview transcripts and excerpts.
  • "Banking," U.S. Steel Concert Hour, March 17, 1961
  • "Lewis Quotes Chase Manhattan Board Chairman on Individualism," Fulton Lewis Jr. Program, WOR and MBS, Dec. 16, 1965
  • "Echoes Champion Call for 'Hard Answers' on East-West Trade," News Commentary with Jeffrey St. John, WRFM (New York), May 2, 1967
  • "Meet the Press," guest: Dr. Leon H. Sullivan, founder, Opportunities Industrialization Centers, March 7, 1971
  • George Champion interviewed by Jessica Holland, 1211 Avenue of the Americas, May 19, 1982
- Newspaper clippings, 1931, 1949-1950, 1956-1957 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  • "New Canal Head To Arrive Friday," New Orleans, La. States, Feb. 26, 1931
  • "Chase Bank Shifts Five High Officers," New York Times, Jan. 27, 1949
  • "Named Directors of Better Business Bureau," New York Herald Tribune, May 29, 1950
  • "Champion President of Chase Manhattan; David Rockefeller is Named Vice-Chairman," American Banker, Dec. 13, 1956
  • "Market Goes Into New Dip" [John Rogers column mentioning Champion's election], Daily News, Dec. 13, 1956
  • "Chase Names G. Champion New President," Journal of Commerce and Commercial, Dec. 13, 1956
  • "Chase Bank Elects President," New York Herald Tribune, Dec. 13, 1956
  • "Geo. Champion Made President of Chase Man.," New York Journal-American, Dec. 13, 1956
  • "Younger Men Take Top Positions At the Chase Manhattan Bank, New York Times, Dec. 13, 1956
  • "Chase Moves 2 VPs Up Into Top Ranks," New York World-Telegram and Sun, Dec. 13, 1956 [2 editions]
  • "George Champion, 52, Elected President of Chase Manhattan Bank," Wall Street Journal, Dec. 13, 1956
  • "These Are the Men Who Made Their Mark in 1956... In the Worlds of Business and Finance," New York Journal American, Jan. 8, 1957
  • "Board Member Named By American Smelting," New York Times, Feb. 27, 1957
  • George Champion, "As Business Leaders See It... High Business Activity Poses Challenge to Banks," Journal of Commerce and Commercial, May 7, 1957
  • "Billy Graham & Co. to Invade New York," Pittsburgh Press, May 11, 1957 ("While Dr. Graham has long wanted to conduct a crusade in the greatest city in the world, he conscientiously waited until he was actually invited to do so. The invitation was extended by a committee, partly made up of local New York church leaders and partly of business executives. It is headed by George Champion, president of the huge Chase Manhattan Bank.")
  • "Hometowners' Appraisal: Newsboys from Bloomington, Ill., look over copies of Chase Manhattan News, publication of Chase Manhattan Bank, as George Champion, president of the bank and a native son of Bloomington, awaits comment," New York World-Telegram and Sun, Dec. 11, 1957 [2 photocopies]
- Newspaper clippings, 1960-1969 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  • "Industry Aid For Asia Asked By Champion," New York Herald Tribune, May 24, 1960
  • "Chase Bank Names Champion Chairman, D. Rockefeller President, Effective in 1961," Wall Street Journal, Oct. 21, 1960 [2 copies]
  • "Champion and Rockefeller to Head Chase Bank Jan. 1," American Banker, Oct. 21, 1960, sent to Champion by Richard G. Stockton with clipping of "Rising Money Needs of Colleges Discussed," [unidentified newspaper], Sep. 15, 1960
  • "Normal Native New Chairman of Chase Bank," Bloomington, Ill. Pantagraph, Oct. 23, 1960 [3 copies]
  • "Personality: A Bank Chief With Capital 'C,' New York Times, Oct. 30, 1960
  • "Bank President Champion Tells Formula for Success," Bloomington, Ill. Pantagraph, Nov. 20, 1960
  • "Chase Bank Picks a New Chairman," [unidentified newspaper], [month and date lacking], 1960
  • "New RCA Plant Dedicated," West Palm Beach, Fla. Post, May 26, 1961
  • "Banker Says Tax Cut is Practical," San Diego Union, Oct. 17, 1961
  • "[word missing]—Bankers Cast Austerity Shadow," Christian Science Monitor, Oct. 18, 1961
  • "Reserve Bank Names Directors," New York World-Telegram and The Sun, Nov. 28, 1961
  • "Two Joining Board of Reserve Bank," New York Times, Nov. 28, 1961
  • "Directors of N.Y. Fed," New York Herald Tribune, Nov. 28, 1961
  • "NY Reserve Bank Elects Director," Journal of Commerce, Nov. 28, 1961
  • "Champion and Puckett Elected Directors of Federal Reserve Bank of New York," American Banker, Nov. 28, 1961
  • "Executive Changes: Champion, Puckett On Fed. Bank Board," New York Journal-American, Nov. 28, 1961
  • Jack Craddock, "Portrait of a Banker: George Champion," American Banker, Oct. 6, 1962 [3 copies]
  • "Sees His Duty, Does It," Nashville Tennessean, Nov. 10, 1963 [photo with caption "NEW YORK—Waiter pouring wine doesn't interrupt flow of President Kennedy's conversation as the chief executive chats with George Champion, board chairman of Chase Manhattan Bank, during annual banquet of Protestant Council of the City of New York. Champion was chairman of the affair, at which Kennedy became the first Roman Catholic to receive the council's 'Family of Man' award.]
  • "President Kennedy is served by a waiter at banquet Friday night sponsored by the New York City Protestant Council during conversation with George Champion (left), chairman of the board of the Chase Manhattan National Bank," [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "New York Protestants to Honor President," [unidentified, undated publication]
  • "Alfalfa Club Selects a Champion Candidate," Washington, D.C. Sunday Star, Jan. 26, 1964 [photocopy]
  • "Chase Salad Oil Loss Totals $9.8 Million," New York World-Telegram, Jan. 28, 1964
  • "Chase Bad Debt: Salad Oil Loans," New York Herald Tribune, Jan. 29, 1964
  • "Claims Against American Express Unit Mount to $81 Million in Salad Oil Scandal," Wall Street Journal, Jan. 29, 1964
  • "Senator Hopes One Extravagance, Congress, Will Survive," [unidentified newspaper, but either the Sacramento Bee, the Fresno Bee, or the Modesto Bee], Feb. 10, 1964
  • "Nixon Asks Raids on Reds in Asia," New York Times, Apr. 17, 1964
  • "Detroit Free Press agrees with Richard Nixon.. .," New York Post, Apr. 17, 1964
  • "Nixon Warns on Asia," New York Herald Tribune, Apr. 17, 1964
  • "Women and Men—Women and Money," Charlotte News, Jan. 17, 1964 [photocopy]
  • "Leading Banker scans payments-balance issue," Christian Science Monitor, March 11, 1965
  • "Honorary Degree" (photo caption: "George H. Champion, chairman of the board of the Chase Manhattan Bank of New York City, receives the doctor of law degree during commencement exercises Sunday [June 6, 1965] at Millikin University. Millikin President Paul L. McKay, right, looks on. Champion was the commencement speaker. About 170 students were graduated in the ceremonies."), Decatur Herald, June 7, 1965 [3 copies]
  • "Automation and Its Potential," Champaign, Ill. News-Gazette, June 13, 1965
  • "Heads of 10 Largest Banks in Free World at Year-end," American Banker, Aug. 2, 1965
  • "Chase Exec Urges European Aid Cut to End U.S. Deficit," New York World-Telegram and The Sun, Aug. 17, 1965
  • "Champion Urges Cut in U.S. Aid," New York Journal-American, Aug. 17, 1965
  • "Cut Urged in Aid to Europe," New York Times, Aug. 18, 1965
  • "Payments: 1st Surplus in 8 Years," New York Herald Tribune, Aug. 18, 1965
  • "Champion: Exclude Export Credits From BofP Plan," American Banker, Aug. 18, 1965
  • "The 'Consensus Complex' vs. Free Market," New York Journal-American, Nov. 19, 1965
  • "Chase Bank Official Lays 'Consensus Complex' to U.S.," New York Herald Tribune, Nov. 19, 1965
  • "Bank Speaker Hits at Rule By Consensus," Washington, D.C. Star, Nov. 19, 1965
  • "'Consensus Complex' Stifles Criticism of Govt., Champion Says," American Banker, Nov. 19, 1965
  • "N.Y. Bank Chairman 'Threats' to Free Market Described," Denver Post, Nov. 19, 1965 [2 copies]
  • "Banker Says Russ Economy Offers Lesson," Denver, Colo., Rocky Mountain News, Nov. 19, 1965
  • "Banker Raps 'Papa Knows Best' in D.C.," Daily News, Nov. 19, 1965
  • "Chase Bank Chairman Hits Government by 'Consensus'," Wall Street Journal, Nov. 19, 1965
  • "'Consensus Complex': Banker Attacks Washington," New York Herald Tribune (Paris Edition), Nov. 19, 1965
  • "Banker Urges Dissent," New York Times, Nov. 19, 1965
  • "Freedom to Disagree," Albany, N.Y. Times-Union, Nov. 20, 1965
  • "George Champion, chairman of Chase Manhattan Bank.. .," Des Moines, Iowa Register, Nov. 20, 1965
  • "Financial View in New York. Not-So-Golden Silence," New York Herald Tribune, Nov. 21, 1965
  • "Profit Plan Adopted by Russians?," Miami, Fla. Herald, Nov. 21, 1965
  • "'Consensus Complex' Hit By Bank Head," Journal of Commerce & Commercial, Nov. 23, 1965
  • "A Banker Looks at America," Decatur, Ala. Daily, Nov. 24, 1965
  • "Dangers of 'Consensus Complex," Fort Wayne, Ind. News-Sentinel, Nov. 25, 1965
  • "LBJ-Business Honeymoon Sours," Centralia, Wash. Chronicle, Nov. 26, 1965
  • "Consensus or Conformity?," Newport, R.I. News, Nov. 26, 1965
  • "The Consensus Complex," Oneida, N.Y. Dispatch, Nov. 27, 1965
  • "Challenge for LBJ," Reading, Penn. Eagle, Nov. 27, 1965
  • "Consensus, or Conformity," Connellsville, Penn. Courier, Nov. 27, 1965
  • "Consensus or Conformity?," Haleyville, Ala. Northwest Alabamian, Nov. 28, 1965
  • "Business Attitude Cooling Toward LBJ & Company," Miami, Fla. Herald, Nov. 28, 1965
  • "Johnson's Relations With Business Cooler," Decatur, Ill. Herald and Review, Nov. 28, 1965
  • "'Consensus' and Inconsistency," Lewiston, Maine Journal, Nov. 29, 1965
  • "Lessons for the U.S.," Monroe, La. World, Dec. 1, 1965
  • "Notable & Quotable," Wall Street Journal, Dec. 1, 1965
  • "The Uses of Altruism," Wall Street Journal, March 28, 1966
  • "Inauguración en Madrid de la XIII Conferencia Monetaria de la American Bankers Association," ABC, 25 May 1966
  • "He'd Have Business Lead In Solving U.S. Problems," Bloomington, Ill. Daily Pantagraph, May 31, 1966
  • "Politics Public Business," [unidentified newspaper], July 3, 1966
  • "Consensus Complex," Seymour, Ind. Tribune, July 5, 1966
  • "If Business Took Initiative," Lafayette, Ind. Journal & Courier, July 11, 1966
  • "Capital's Role in Labor Talks," World Journal Tribune, Feb. 16, 1967 [2 copies]
  • "Chase Chief Attacks Ending of 7% Tax Credit," New York Times, Feb. 17, 1967
  • "Restore 7% Tax Credit to Spur Biz: Chase Chief," Daily News, Feb. 17, 1967
  • "Restoration of 7% Tax Credit Called For by Chase Chairman," Washington Post, Feb. 17, 1967
  • "Capital's Labors," Wall Street Journal, Feb. 24, 1967 [2 copies]
  • "World Bankers Begin Conference," Washington Post, March 15, 1967
  • "Chase Convening Big Parley in Rio," New York Times, March 13, 1967
  • "Champion Hails Brazil, Argentina," World Journal Tribune, March 13, 1967
  • "Chase Bank Sets Record Here in Signing $200-Million Lease," New York Times, March 14, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Chase Leases Huge Space," World Journal Tribune, March 13, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Business News Highlights," Journal of Commerce, March 14, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Chase Manhattan Signs Lease," Wall Street Journal, March 14, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Chase Signs Top Lease," Daily News, March 14, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Chase Signs Lease," New York Post, March 14, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Chase Signs Record Lease for NY Skyscraper Space," American Banker, March 14, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Prime Rate Reduced by Major Banks," Washington Post, March 23, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Morgan Guaranty Cuts Prime Rate to Chase's Level," New York Times, March 23, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Business and Finance," Wall Street Journal, March 23, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "More Banks Cut Loan Rate," Daily News, March 23, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Morgan Guaranty Reduces Prime Rate to 5 ½ % Level," Wall Street Journal, March 23, 1967 [photocopy]
  • "Grinnell College Schedules Convocation," Grinnell, Iowa, Grinnell Herald-Register, Aug. 28, 1967
  • "Banks Cautioned on Job Equality," New York Times, September 27, 1967
  • "Champion Stresses Jobs in Call For Minority Group Advancement," American Banker, Sep. 27, 1967
  • "Banks Told to Become Involved," Chicago Sun Times, Sep. 27, 1967
  • "Chase Bank Head Calls for Incentives in Welfare System," New York Times, Oct. 30, 1967
  • "Banker Visitor to Adelaide," [unidentified Australian newspaper], Nov. 24, 1967
  • "Man of Year," [Grand Rapids Times?], Dec. 5, 1967
  • "Business Giants Help Form OIC Council to Assist Negro Youths," Philadelphia Tribune, March 30, 1968
  • "Chase Manhattan Job Training Program Gives Dropouts a Chance to Drop Back In," American Banker, June 18, 1968
  • "Democrats Would Keep This a Secret," Herald Traveler, July 9, 1968
  • "Champion Pleads Action on Inflation," New York Times, Oct. 8, 1968
  • "Chase Bank Chairman New OIC Council Head," New York Amsterdam News, Jan. 25, 1969
  • "Capital VIPs Remember IKE," Pittsburgh Press, Nov. 30, 1969
  • "Banking on Blacks: Chase Manhattan Bank Recruits in the Ghetto, and Results are Mixed," Wall Street Journal, Dec. 23, 1969
- Newspaper clippings, 1970-1979 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  • "Nixon's Inner Circle Here Remains Close to Him," New York Times, Jan. 17, 1970
  • "Nixon's New York Friends Still Play Personal Roles," Richmond, Va. Times-Dispatch, Jan. 18, 1970
  • "Straus Gets Gold Medal Award," Daily News, Oct. 7, 1970 [photo caption: "Jack I. Straus (left), executive committee chairman of R. H. Macy & Co., accepts 1970 Gold Medal Award of the Hundred Year Association of New York from George Champion, president of the Economic Development Council of New York City. Award is given annually in recognition of an individual's civic and philanthropic contributions to the city. Presentation was made at the Waldorf-Astoria Hotel."]
  • "[missing word] Pressing Hard [fo]r 'Incomes Policy'," Washington Post, [date missing], 1970
  • "College, Training Unit Share $50,000 Grant," New York Amsterdam News, Jan. 16, 1971 [photocopy]
  • "College for Human Services and O.I.C. Share Chase Manhattan's George Champion Service Award," East Side News, Jan. 22, 1971
  • "Manpower Training Report Asks Reforms," Jamaica, N.Y., Long Island Press, Jan. 27, 1971
  • "Tribute: After presenting the 1970 George Champion Awards.. .," Chicago, Ill. Jet, Jan. 28, 1971
  • "O.I.C. of America Founder Announces Ten Million Dollar Fund Drive," Fort Pierce, Fla. Chronicle, Jan. 28, 1971
  • "City's Manpower Training Is 'Disjointed,' Study Finds," New York Times, Jan. 27, 1971
  • "Retired N.Y. Banker Aids in Shaping City's Course," Newark, N.J. Evening News, May 12, 1971
  • "Urban Crisis Blamed on City Inefficiency," Los Angeles Times, Oct. 6, 1971
  • "ACAPULCO—The big news in the opening of the $40 million Acapulco Princess Hotel.. .," [San Diego Tribune?], circa Dec. 2, 1971
  • "Executives Counseling Students," New York Times, May 22, 1972
  • "Privileged Pensioners," Daily News, Oct. 3, 1972
  • "Edmund Leopold de Rothschild, chairman of N. M. Rothschild & Sons, Ltd., of Great Britain, received an award yesterday in Tokyo called 'the First Class Order of the Sacred Treasure'," New York Times, April 17, 1973
  • "The Only Answer: Economy," Daily News, Dec. 2, 1974
  • "An open letter to the President and the Congress of the United States," New York Times, Dec. 27, 1974
  • "Never Say Die: The City of the Future," Daily News, Dec. 28, 1975
  • "Number as well as name proposed for U.S. babies," New York Post, April 26, 1977 [photocopy]
  • "Report to Put the No-Shows on the Road," Daily News, May 25, 1977
  • "Schools Not Up to Grade, Business Leader Asserts," Daily News, June 8, 1977
  • George Champion, "Five Plank Proposal Advanced to Complete City's 'Turnaround'," New York Law Journal, June 27, 1977
  • "Turning the Tide," Daily News, Aug. 21, 1977
  • "Managing the City," Daily News, Nov. 28, 1977
  • "A real champion," [unidentified newspaper, circa 1977; photocopy]
  • "Study Says New York Transit Pay Outpaces Raises in Private Sector," New York Times, Jan. 16, 1978
  • "Ready, Aim, Fire," Daily News, Jan. 17, 1978
  • "Our failing schools," Daily News, Oct. 18, 1979 [original + photocopy]
- Newspaper clippings, 1983-2019, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  • "Foreign Debts: A Proposal for U.S. Banks," New York Times, Jan. 11, 1983 [2 originals + 3 photocopies]
  • "Be Careful Reforming Bank Regulation," Wall Street Journal, Jan. 18, 1984
  • George Champion, "A Banking System in Trouble. Regulators and Bankers Are to Blame," New York Times, June 10, 1984 [original + 2 photocopies]
  • "Bankers Remember the Great Crash of 1929," American Banker, Nov. 4, 1987
  • "Former Chase Manhattan boss denounces 'big' in banks," Asbury Park Press, July 28, 1991
  • "The former boss of Chase Manhattan speaks out," Stamford Advocate, July 28, 1991
  • "At 90, German Banker Turns Author," New York Times, Nov. 12, 1991
  • "The Company as Family, No More," New York Times, March 4, 1996
  • "George Champion, 93, Head of Chase Manhattan in 1960's," New York Times, Sep. 22, 1997
  • "Bank's Secret Campaign to Win Entry to U.S. for Shah of Iran," New York Times, Dec. 29, 2019
  • "A New Kind of Partnership" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Bank President Champion Tells Formula for Success" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Banker's Advice: Speak Out" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Champion Tells Middlebury Audience: Equilibrium in Balance-of-Payments Should Get Top Priority by Nation" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Chase Bank Chairman Assails Steps to Expand National Banks' Powers" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Chase Gets Nigerian License" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Government by Pressure" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Leading the Way" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "The Positive Thinker. Norman Vincent Peale is Criticized, but Many Listen to His Message" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Savings at Chase Top Billion Mark," New York Journal American, [no date]